# Vanessa Nimmo

vanessa.nimmo@gmail.com 0438 464 939 https://github.com/VanessaNimmo

I'm a Protege Developer at MYOB who, having recently joined the industry, is hoping to learn a great deal, work with great deal, and work on interesting projects that help people.

#### **Skills**

- Coding in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Ruby and Ruby on Rails
- Experience with Git, SQL, YellowFin and Keboola
- Writing academic, copywriting, essay, documentation
- Teaching and workshop leading for all ages from one-on-one to groups of up to 100 people
- Administrative and financial competency for running a small-medium arts business, including interstate touring and event management
- Composition, arranging, songwriting, sound design, sound effects

## Education, Workshops and Conferences

DDD (2018) GovHack (2018) RubyConfAU (2018)

Tech Inclusion Conference Melbourne (2018) Rails Girls Workshop (2018)

Coursera Java Courses (2017) DataGirls Workshop (2017)

School of Music, Australian National University (2009) - Bachelor of Music (Composition)
Associate of Trinity College London (2015) - Voice performance qualification
Melbourne Conservatorium of Music, Melbourne University (2016) - First Class Honours
(Music Research and Performance)

#### **Achievements**

Best Music at the 2015 Melbourne Fringe Festival for the experimental soundscape *Old Tech New Decks*.

Best Score at the 2015 Canberra Short Film Festival for *A Song*.

Adelaide Fringe 2016 Weekly Award (Highly Commended) and nomination for the John Chattaway Innovation Award for *Old Tech New Decks*.

### Experience

Protege Developer at MYOB (2018 - present)

Joined MYOB in August 2018, where my job thus far has been to learn.

Freelance musician and teacher (2002 - 2018)

I've taught at music schools in Canberra and Melbourne, conducted an orchestra, composed music for a short film, been an Assistant Director for kids theatre, been a piano accompanist, and performed and written cabaret shows, among other activities. For many years I was Head of Theory at Parkville Music School, where I was responsible for training new teachers, preparing students for exams and liaising with parents and the Director of the Music School. I've also introduced technology into the classroom, in the form of iPads and computers, and am responsible for the maintenance of these.

Swing and Blues Dance Instructor, DJ and Tech Coordinator (2011 – Present)

Vintage jazz and blues DJ and instructor for local and national events including White Night 2017 in Melbourne and Ballarat. In the past year I have stepped into more senior roles, curating and organising DJ teams and running live sound for weekly dances and events. Jazz music and dance is a passion of mine, so as well as paid positions in these areas I often volunteer my time to the community.

Composer, Producer, Performer: Old Tech New Decks (2015 - 2017)

After having the idea for this show in March 2015, I invited fellow composer Matthew Rankin to join me in creating this experimental soundscape for the Melbourne Fringe Festival. After a highly successful run at the 2015 Melbourne Fringe, we toured the show to the 2016 Adelaide Fringe. As well as composing, writing and performing the show

collaboratively, I was individually responsible for marketing, producing and budget tracking for the show. At the end of 2016 we composed and recorded an album as part of a residency at the Footscray Artsbox, where we created a recording studio for the sounds of old technology and then composed music using these sampled sounds. This album was released in 2017.

Volunteer Treasurer: Jumptown Swing, Canberra (2010–2011)

Joining the organization after a period of inactivity in the Treasurer's role, I collaborated with another volunteer to bring 2 years of accounts up to date and produce financial reports using MYOB, fulfilling Jumptown Swing's legal obligations as a not-for-profit and allowing it to continue operating as such. We then created a streamlined system to allow the volunteer-run organization to continue with less financial work involved.

#### **Interests**

Jazz and blues music and dance, hiking and horse riding in the high country.

I'm part of two-person blogging team King Nimmo on Medium, where we write about our experiences of learning and discovery in tech: <a href="https://medium.com/@nimmoking">https://medium.com/@nimmoking</a>